Humane Borders records, 2000-2010 MS 471
University of Arizona
- Series III: Administrative Files, 2000-2011
  - Subseries 6: Reports and Studies, 2000-2009
    - GAO-03-660T Homeland Security Challenges, April 10, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 37)
    - GAO-03-1094R Land Border Ports of Entry, August 18, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 38)
    - GAO-04-472 Hospitals' Care Costs, May 2004 (Box 19, Folder 39)
    - GAO-04-590 DHS Coordination with Federal Agencies, June 2004 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - About GAO, July 19, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Federal Immigration Law Enforcement in the Southwest, March 1997 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - University of Houston Report, March 2001 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - INS Statistics, April 26, 2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Hold the Line Report, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Migration Policy Institute, April 2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Tragedy Along the Arizona-Mexico Border, August 23, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Position Paper, November 20, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Deaths, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Report from the Border 2003, February 13, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Report from the Border 2003, February 13, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Report from the Border 2003, February 13, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Report from the Border 2003 original, February 13, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Report from the Border 2003, February 13, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - HB: Environmental Assessment for Rescue Beacons, June 2003 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Draft of Environmental Assessment for Temporary Checkpoint, Ajo Station, July 2003 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Project to Mitigate Environmental Degradation Caused by Illegal Immigrants End of Year Report, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Comision Nacional De Derechos Humanos, 2004-2009 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - Refuges at Risk, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    - Immigration from Heartland Chicago Council, June 2004 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    - Year End to Feds, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    - Project to Address Public Land Degradation as a Result of Illegal Immigration, End of Year Report, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    - Migrantes, un rostro de Mexico, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    - Guia del Migrante Mexicano, January 27, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    - Role of Immigrants in U.S. Labor Market, November 2005 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    - Mapping Migrant Deaths in Southern Arizona: The Humane Borders GIS, September 8, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    - Declaration of San Xavier, October 1, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    - Humane Borders Water Station Report 2006, January 30, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    - Anti-Essentialism, March 2, 2007 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Cell Tower Environmental Impact Study, July 2007-July 2008 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Planning Response to Migrant Deaths in Southern Arizona, August 2007 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Health and Migration: Women Who Cross the U.S.-Mexico Border, Spring 2008 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Environmental Assessment for Proposed SBInet Tucson West Project, May 2008 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Reunion de trabajo previa a la Integracion del Comite Regional contra la Trata de Personas, June 18, 2008 (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Federal Regulation 7885 U.S. Immigration Policy and Human Rights, July 2009 (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Chaos on the Border Clinic Report, undated (Box 20, Folder 35)
    - Chertoff's Waiver Announcement from DHS Website, April 1, no year (Box 20, Folder 36)
    - Death, Life, Sacrifice, undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Estados Unidos-Mexico Muros, Abusos y Muertos en las fronteras, undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
    - Presentation, undated (Box 20, Folder 39)
    - Protecting the Rights of Immigrants and Asylum Seekers in Post 9-11, undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
    - Unity Blueprint for Immigration Reform, undated (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Subseries 7: Water Trip Reports and Schedules, 2002-2009
    This subseries is in rough chronological order with reports for water stations in the same location grouped together. The reports and schedules document the refilling of the Humane Borders water stations and trash pickup efforts.
    - BANWR/Coleman Rd, 2003-2004 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - BA Brawley, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - BANWR, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Trip Reports BA-Brawley, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - HB Cochise County Border Road, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Trip Report: Cochise-Border Rd, 2007 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Coleman Rd 3 points, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Coleman Rd, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Trip Report: Coleman Rd - 3 Points, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Trip Reports: OP (Organ Pipe)- Ajo, 2002-2004 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Organ Pipe Cactus NM, 2005-2006 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - OPCNM, 2007-2008 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Trip Report: OPCNM - Ajo Block, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Arivaca - Gr Valley, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Arivaca - Green Valley, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Green Valley/Arivaca South, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Trip Report: IFNM - Manville, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Trip Schedules, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Water Trip Schedule, 2006 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Water Trip Schedules, January 1, 2008-December 31, 2007 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Water Trip Schedules, January 1, 2008-December 31, 2008 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Water Trip Schedules, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Cooper Dragoon Stations, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Rio Rico, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Trip Reports Elephant Head, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Wilson, 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Mike Wilson, 2005-2008 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Mike Wilson, 2009 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Ajo Inspections, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Trip Reports Cochise, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - IFNM, 2003-2004 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - IFNM, 2005-2006 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Ironwood, 2007-2008 (Box 22, Folder 16)
- Series IV: Awards, November 2001-February 2008
  This subseries is arranged chronologically and contains material pertaining to awards that Humane Borders has received.
  - Leo B. Hart Humanitarian Award, June 5, 2001, November 9, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Season for Non Violence Award, April 7, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Caesar Chavez Award, February 21, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Voice of Conscience Award, June 6, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - C.V. Nomination Materials for CNDH Mexico Award, October 2006-December 2006 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Meyer and Libby Marmis Humanitarian Award (nom. By B. Feinman), February 2008 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Tucson, Arizona Humane Borders Day, June 11, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Series V: Maps and Oversize Material, 2001-2004
  This series is comprised of poster and map material. The maps have been transferred to the Library where they are cataloged and identified as part of these records.
  - 2000-2004 Cell coverage map and deaths (Box 24, Item 1)
  - Pima, Yuma, Pinal, Cochise, Maricopa and Santa Cruz surface management maps (Box 24, Item 2)
  - No Olvidado Not Forgotten 1999-2003 (Box 24, Item 3)
  - Border Patrol Map 2001 Deaths by type (Box 24, Item 4)
  - 2000-2004 Cumulative Deaths Map, 2003 (Box 24, Item 5)
  - Arizona Republic article, "A Lonely Place to Die", October 16, 2003 (Box 24, Item 6)
  - Properties owned by Pima County (Box 24, Item 7)
  - Reaping the Benefits Poster, circa 2006-2007 (Box 24, Item 8)
  - Grupo Beta Posters, March 2003-May 2003 (Box 24, Item 9)
  - Gatekeeper Posters, 2006 (Box 24, Item 10)
  - School poster of check (their donation), November 13, 2006 (Box 24, Item 11)